I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
（竜介(りゅうすけ)）う…
"Fishing Hole"
Damn...
（竜介）チクショウ
"Live 19
'Blues'"
He's probably walking Beck.
散歩[さんぽ]:walk/stroll
（タマヨ）ベックの散歩
行ったんじゃないの？
For two days?
（サク）えっ ２日も？
He hasn't contacted you...
連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
（コユキ）
連絡 ないんですよね？
（タマヨ）メイビー
Maybe...
（千葉(ちば)）ハァ…
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
（千葉）んんっ おい ばあちゃん！
心配じゃねえのかよ？
Hey, Grandma, aren't you worried?!
なあああ！
（コユキ・サク）いや…
No thanks...
Looks like Lucille's gone, too.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（コユキ）ルシールもないみたい
That guy...
（平(たいら)）あいつ… んっ！
男性[だんせい]:man/male|masculine gender, 京都[きょうと]:Kyoto, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
（男性２）
京都に来たいなんて—
He wants to go to Kyoto...
Leon-san seems quite fond of Japan.
結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, 親日[しんにち]:pro-Japanese, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
レオンさん 結構な
親日家なんですねえ
Yeah...I heard he was
influenced by his uncle.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother), 影響[えいきょう]:influence/effect|to influence
（司会者）ああ 確か
叔父の影響だって—
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
聞いたことがあるけどな
Oh?
へえ～
幼い[おさない, いとけない]:very young|childish/immature, 頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), 叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother), 引き取る[ひきとる]:to take over|to take charge of|to retire to a private place, 育てる[そだてる]:to raise|to train|to promote the growth of
彼は幼い頃から 叔父に
引き取られて 育てられたそうだよ
His uncle took him in when
he was little, and raised him.
叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother), 嫁[よめ]:wife/bride|(one's) daughter-in-law, 日本人[にほんじん, にっぽんじん]:Japanese person/Japanese people
叔父さんの嫁さんが
日本人だったそうだ
Seems his uncle's wife was Japanese.
いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), 成功[せいこう]:success/hit, つかむ:to seize/to catch|to obtain
レオンさんって いろいろあって
成功をつかんだ人なんすね
Leon-san has overcome much
in order to succeed, I guess.
詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well
（司会者）
詳しくは知らんが—
I don't know the details,
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, アジア:Asia (esp. "the Far East"), アングロサクソン:Anglo-Saxon
彼の体には アジア
アングロサクソン アフリカン…
but I hear he's got the blood
of five continents in his veins-
大陸[たいりく]:continent|continental Asia (esp. mainland China)|continental Europe, 血[ち]:blood/consanguinity, 流れる[ながれる]:to stream|to be washed away|to drift||
５つの大陸の血が
流れているそうだよ
including Asian, Anglo-Saxon and African.
５つですかあ
Five?
あくまで:to the end/to the bitter end|after all
まっ あくまでも ウワサだがね
Of course, it's just a rumor.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
何か… 怖いんですけど
-I find him a little scary.
-Yeah...
ゴール:goal/basket (basketball)/finishing line, ディー:D/d, 英語[えいご]:English (language)
（ゴールディー：英語）
〈ボス！〉
Hi, Boss...
部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable
〈部屋には俺１人ですよ〉
Well, I'm here myself.
買い物[かいもの]:shopping/purchased goods
〈みんなは秋葉原(あきはばら)で
買い物じゃないっすか〉
I guess everyone is shopping
in Akihabara right now.
〈あの男？〉
That man?
〈大丈夫ですよ〉
That's fine.
ボコボコ:burbling
〈ボコボコにしてやりましたから〉
I beat the hell outta him.
He won't even think
of running away from us.
逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
〈もう逃げようなんて
思いませんよ〉
オーケー:OK
〈オーケー 10時に
東京(とうきょう)駅っすね〉
Okay, 10 o'clock. Tokyo Station?
ジャスト:just/perfect/exact, 迎える[むかえる]:to go out to meet|to receive|to accept (e.g. as a member of a group or family)||
〈ジャストに迎えに
行きますよ ボス〉
I'll pick you up on time, Boss.
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
（女の子）嫌～っ！
（竜介）んんっ!! ふんっ！
（ゴールディー）ああっ！
Fucking blood on my...I can't believe
this muthafucker hit me in the head!
I'll kill you, little fucker!
Damn it! You really pissed me off!
ムカつく:to feel irritated/to feel offended|to feel sick
（ゴールディー）〈チクショウ！
マジでムカつくヤローだぜ！〉
司会者[しかいしゃ]:chairman/moderator/toastmaster, 英語[えいご]:English (language), ミスター:mister/Mr
（司会者：英語）
〈ミスターサイクス！〉
Mister Sykes...
方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||, 御存知[ごぞんじ]:knowing|(an) acquaintance
〈ジョン・リー・デイビスという方を
御存知ですか？〉
Do you know the guy
called John Lee Davis?
会社[かいしゃ]:company/corporation|workplace, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
〈会社に連絡がありました〉
He called you at the office.
He's in Japan right now as
a backup band for a soul singer.
往年[おうねん]:former/one-time/years ago, 人気[にんき]:popularity/public favor|condition (e.g. market), 人気[ひとけ]:sign of life/human presence|humanity, ソウル:soul, シンガー:singer
〈彼は今 往年の
人気ソウルシンガーの—〉
バック:back, バック:bag, バンド:band, 来日[らいにち]:arrival in Japan/coming to Japan/visit to Japan, 来日[らいじつ]:future day/later date
〈バックバンドとして
来日中なんだそうです〉
Oh...I haven't seen him for three years...
英語[えいご]:English (language)
（レオン：英語）
〈もう ３年も会ってないな〉
Oh?
叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother)
（レオン）〈ジョン・リー・デイビスは
私の叔父だ〉
He, John Lee Davis, is my uncle.
たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous, テレビ:television/TV
（司会者）
〈たぶんテレビでも見てて—〉
He must have gotten to know Mr. Sykes'
coming to Japan, by TV or something.
ミスター:mister/Mr, 来日[らいにち]:arrival in Japan/coming to Japan/visit to Japan, 来日[らいじつ]:future day/later date
〈ミスターサイクスの来日を
知ったんでしょう〉
店[みせ]:store/shop/establishment, 店[てん]:-store/-shop
（ゴールディー）
〈店の名前 クロスロードですか〉
Cross Road? That's classic...
〈ちょっとベタですね〉
店[みせ]:store/shop/establishment, 店[てん]:-store/-shop, 叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother)
〈その店に叔父さんが
いるんですか？〉
Is your uncle there at that restaurant?
叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother), 来日[らいにち]:arrival in Japan/coming to Japan/visit to Japan, 来日[らいじつ]:future day/later date, 必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily, 店[みせ]:store/shop/establishment, 店[てん]:-store/-shop, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
〈叔父が来日すると
必ず行く店らしい〉
Yeah. He always goes there
when he visits Japan.
I see. Anyway Boss,
why do we wanna bring him?
（ゴールディー）
〈それにしても ボス〉
連れていく[つれていく, つれてゆく]:to take someone (to some place)/to take someone along/to lead someone away
〈何で こいつまで
連れていくんです？〉
Punk ass never does anything, anywhere.
見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
〈ルシールが見つかって—〉
I told him that we found the Lucille,
and that a Japanese musician stole it.
犯人[はんにん]:offender/criminal, 日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, ミュージシャン:musician, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
〈犯人が日本のミュージシャン
だったと話したら—〉
〈彼に会いたいと言われた〉
And now, he wants to see him.
面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care
（ゴールディー）〈面倒なことに
なりませんかね？〉
Isn't it going to be too much trouble?
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|
〈犬はどうしてる？〉
How's that dog?
Hmph...He'll never take to me.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, なつく:to become emotionally attached
（ゴールディー）
〈全然 なつきませんね〉
ブルース:blues
（レオン）〈ブルース〉
The blues...
〈ロバート・ジョンソンか〉
Sounds like Robert Johnson...
英語[えいご]:English (language), 意外[いがい]:unexpected/surprising
（竜介：英語）〈意外だな〉
Surprising...
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, 亡者[もうじゃ]:the dead, レーベル:label (i.e. sticker), 陰[いん]:yin (i.e. the negative)|unseen location (i.e. somewhere private), 陰[かげ]:shade/shadow|other side
〈金の亡者
ＲＪレーベルの陰のボス—〉
Money mad boss, Leon Sykes,
talk about Robert Johnson?
口[くち]:mouth|opening|mouth (of a bottle)||, 口[く, こう]:mouth/speech|counter for people or implements
〈レオン・サイクスの口から—〉
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
〈ロバート・ジョンソンの
名前が出るなんてな〉
英語[えいご]:English (language)
（デイビス：英語）
〈おお レオンじゃないか！〉
Hey...Leon!
Come on...What are you putting
on that dreadful face for?
〈おいおい！〉
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
〈そんな怖い顔して
何考えてんだい？〉
I wouldn't sue you for money
like your dad did.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 裁判[さいばん]:trial/judgement/judgment, 起こす[おこす]:to raise|to wake|to cause||
〈俺はお前のトーチャン
みたいに裁判起こして—〉
Come on, Leon. This is
your Uncle John Lee Davis!
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, 巻き上げる[まきあげる]:to roll up|to take away|to blow up (dust), なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
〈お前さんから
金 巻き上げようなんて—〉
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
〈考えてねぇから心配すんな！〉
〈ジョン〉
John...
〈レオン〉
Leon...
そいつ:he/she|that, 例[れい]:custom|said|instance|, 例[ためし]:precedent/example, 日本人[にほんじん, にっぽんじん]:Japanese person/Japanese people
（デイビス）
〈そいつが例の日本人かい？〉
Is that the Japanese?
（レオン）
〈ああ リュースケ・ミナミ〉
Yeah. Ryusuke Minami.
The fucked up punk
who used a picture of Lucille
シカゴ:Chicago, インディーズ:indies/independent film or music
〈シカゴのインディーズから—〉
ジャケット:jacket, アルバム:album
〈ルシールをジャケットに使った
アルバムを出した—〉
for the album jacket that was released
by an Indies label in Chicago.
〈イカれた野郎さ〉
（ゴールディー）
〈何とか言え！〉
Say somethin'!
洗う[あらう]:to wash|to inquire into|to purify (one's heart)|
〈ちょっと手を洗ってきます〉
I'm gonna go wash my hands.
Yeah...
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, プレイ:play/erotic play (esp. S&M)
（竜介）〈さっきのプレイ
聞いて思ったんですけど〉
I was listening to you play, earlier.
Hey, brat...You still alive?
小僧[こぞう]:youngster|young Buddhist priest|young shopboy
〈おう 小僧〉
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
〈生きてたか？〉
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
（竜介）〈もしかしたら—〉
You might be Mr. John Lee Davis?
ミスター:mister/Mr
〈あなたは ミスター
ジョン・リー・デイビスですか？〉
（デイビス）〈ほう！〉
Good...Now what about this?
〈じゃあ これは分かるかい？〉
サンフランシスコ:San Francisco, 演奏[えんそう]:musical performance
〈1964年の
サンフランシスコでの演奏ですね〉
That's from the gigs
in San Francisco, 1964.
（レオン）〈おいおい〉
Hey...When were you born?
いったい:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")/...in the world (e.g. "why in the world?")|one object, いったい:region/zone/whole place, 生まれる[うまれる]:to be born
〈お前さん いったい
いつ生まれたんだい？〉
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments
〈頼む 最後に
ミスターデイビスと—〉
Let me play with Mr. Davis, for my last...
セッション:session
〈セッションさせてほしい〉
弾ける[はじける]:to burst open|to be bursting with (e.g. youth, laughter, flavor)|to bounce
〈お前さん そんな手で
弾けるのかい？〉
Can you play with hands like that?
Fortunately...my left hand is fine.
幸運[こううん]:good luck/fortune, 左手[ひだりて]:left hand|left-hand side/left-hand direction, 左手[ゆんで]:one's left hand/bow hand, 無事[ぶじ]:safety/peace/quietness
（竜介）〈幸運にも
左手は無事なんです〉
〈ほう！〉
Yeah...
ブルース:blues
〈ブルースってやつも
ナカナカいいっすねぇ〉
The blues...It ain't all that bad.
しょせん:after all, しょせん:beginning of hostilities/beginning of competition, ビジネス:business, 向く[むく]:to face|to turn toward|to be suited to, 音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement
（レオン）〈しょせん
ビジネスには向かない音楽さ〉
Not good for business.
Sure ain't gonna make us rich.
ギター:guitar
（竜介）〈あなたのギターを
聞いていると—〉
Your guitar sound
reminds me of Sonny Boy.
サニー:sunny, ボーイ:boy, 思い出す[おもいだす]:to recall/to remember/to recollect
〈なぜかサニーボーイを
思い出します〉
（デイビス）
〈そうかい？ ハハハハ！〉
Is that right?
サニー:sunny, ボーイ:boy, 師匠[ししょう]:master/teacher|coach who owns his stable
〈サニーボーイは
俺の師匠だからな！〉
Sonny Boy is my master.
（竜介）〈マジですか！
じゃ ルシールは？〉
Jesus Christ! Then what about Lucille?
サニー:sunny, ボーイ:boy, 身寄り[みより]:relative
〈サニーボーイは
身寄りのない男でな〉
Sonny Boy had no one to depend on...
以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting
〈俺以外—〉
I was the only one who would
take Lucille on, after him.
引き取る[ひきとる]:to take over|to take charge of|to retire to a private place
〈ルシールを引き取ろうって
ヤツはいなかったのさ〉
But I don't have what
it takes to own Lucille.
器[うつわ]:bowl/vessel|ability, 器[き]:device/instrument|vessel, 過ぎる[すぎる]:to pass through|to pass (i.e. of time)|to have expired||, 過ぎる[よぎる]:to go by/to cross/to pass by
〈でも ルシールは俺の器じゃ
デカ過ぎるシロモンよ〉
ふさわしい:appropriate/adequate/suitable
〈だから ルシールに
ふさわしい—〉
So if the real Blues Man for Lucille
showed up, I'd've handed it over to him.
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal
〈本物のブルースマンが
出てきたら—〉
譲る[ゆずる]:to turn over/to assign|to yield
〈譲るつもりでいたんだよ〉
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal
（竜介）〈あなたは
本物のブルースマンだ！〉
You are the real Blues Man.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement, 捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
（デイビス）〈実は一度
音楽を捨てたことがあってな〉
I gave up the music scene once...
預ける[あずける]:to give into custody/to leave (a child) in the care of|to lean on
〈ルシールは そんとき
レオンに預けたんだよ〉
I left Lucille to Leon, since then.
ミスター:mister/Mr
〈ミスター
ジョン・リー・デイビス〉
Mr. John Lee Davis, it was
a great honor to play with you.
弾ける[はじける]:to burst open|to be bursting with (e.g. youth, laughter, flavor)|to bounce, 光栄[こうえい]:honour/honor/glory, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
〈あなたと弾けて光栄です
ありがとう〉
Thank you.
ドウイタシマシテ
Doitashimashite.
("You're welcome")
タバコ:tobacco/cigarette/cigaret, 吸う[すう]:to smoke|to suck|to absorb|
〈タバコ吸うか？〉
You want a cigarette?
No, thanks.
〈いらねーよ〉
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal
（デイビス）
〈レオン あいつは本物だぞ〉
Leon, he is real.
今まで[いままで]:until now/so far/up to the present, 日本人[にほんじん, にっぽんじん]:Japanese person/Japanese people
〈今まで会った日本人で—〉
I've never seen any Japanese
who could express Blues that good.
ブルース:blues, 理解[りかい]:understanding/comprehension/appreciation
〈彼ほどブルースを
理解している男はいなかった〉
And on top of that, he's really young.
驚く[おどろく]:to be surprised/to be astonished, 若い[わかい]:young|immature|low (number)
〈そのうえ ヤツは
驚くほど若いじゃないか〉
エリカ:erica/heath, 自殺[じさつ]:suicide
〈エリカ・ブライジは
自殺じゃなく 殺されてて—〉
Erica Blige has been murdered,
and I heard rumor that you are the suspect.
しかも:moreover/furthermore|nevertheless, 犯人[はんにん]:offender/criminal
〈しかも犯人は
お前だってウワサを聞いたよ〉
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, エリカ:erica/heath, レーベル:label (i.e. sticker), 批判[ひはん]:criticism/judgement/judgment
〈確かにエリカは
ＲＪレーベルを批判してたからな〉
Erica had been critical of the RJ label.
Leon...Would you kill
people for money, like this?
〈レオン〉
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal, 人殺し[ひとごろし]:murder/murderer
〈金のためなら
人殺しまでするのかい？〉
惜しい[おしい]:regrettable|precious|too good for|
〈ヤツは殺すには惜しい男だぞ〉
He's too good to kill.
叔父[おじ, はくふ]:uncle, 叔父[おとおじ]:uncle (one's father's younger brother)
（レオン）〈叔父さん〉
Uncle...Even though you try to
live straight in this fucked up society...
社会[しゃかい]:society/public|social studies, いくら:how much?/how many?|even, まっとう:proper/respectable|entirely, まっとう:last place (game, race, lottery, etc.), 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
〈こんなクソ社会じゃ
いくらまっとうに生きても—〉
しょせん:after all, しょせん:beginning of hostilities/beginning of competition, しがない:poor/humble|uninteresting, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
〈しょせんは
しがない男で終わるだけだ〉
chances are, you'll die a loser.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, ほとんど:mostly/nearly/practically, しがない:poor/humble|uninteresting
〈それに どうせほとんどの人間が
しがなく死んでいくんだ〉
Most people die that way.
So I...
〈それなら俺は…〉
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement
（竜介）〈クソみたいな音楽だな〉
What a fucking cheesy fucked up music!
（竜介）いて～っ！ ああっ！
Ouch!
（サク）竜介君が
いなくなってから もう４日だね
It's been four days since
Ryusuke-kun disappeared.
Yeah...
警察[けいさつ]:police|police officer|police station, 届ける[とどける]:to deliver/to forward|to report
警察に届けたほうが
いいんじゃないかなあ…
Maybe we should report it to the police.
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
（サク）
もうすぐ ライブあるのにね
It's almost time for our performance.
釣り堀[つりぼり]:fish pond, 届ける[とどける]:to deliver/to forward|to report, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
はっ！ 釣り堀のおばあちゃんに
届け 出してもらおう！
-I'll have the lady at the
fishing hole make a report.
-Hey!
（千葉）お～い!!
（コユキ）ん？
（千葉）
コレコレ！ コレ！ うおおお！
-Take a look at this! Hey!
-Huh? Chiba-kun!
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）ああ！ 千葉君
よいしょ:(expression of) effort or strain/Yo-heave-ho!|to butter up
（サク）
よいしょ どうかしたの？
Uh...Has something happened?
おめえ:you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)|presence (of a god, nobleman, etc.)
何だ おめえら まだ
知らねえんだなあ？
What...You two don't know about it?
フフフ… フ～ン
ジャーン:clash/bang
ジャーン!!
Ta-da!
"Maho Minami"
Ma...ho?
（千葉）フフ～ン
"Maho Minami-Sparkling 16-year-old"
Maho...Minami...
南[みなみ]:south, 南[ナン]:south wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of south wind tiles, 真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
（コユキ）南… 真帆
Maho...Minami...
Sixteen...
歳[さい]:-years-old|ability/gift, 歳[とし]:year|age|past one's prime
16歳…
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 一気[いっき]:chug!/drink! (said repeatedly as a party cheer), ブレイク:break (rest)
（千葉）こりゃあ 真帆のヤツ
一気にブレイクするかもなあ～
"The moment the scent...
of excitement explodes."
She might well become
"The moment the scent...
of excitement explodes."
An overnight sensation.
"The moment the scent...
of excitement explodes."
全国[ぜんこく]:countrywide/nationwide/whole country, おめえ:you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)|presence (of a god, nobleman, etc.), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, かぶりつく:to bite into/to sink one's teeth into|to stick to
全国で おめえらみたいに
かぶりついてるヤツが—
There are guys like you two all over
the nation, who'll be stuck on her.
大勢[おおぜい, たいぜい]:crowd of people/great number of people|in great numbers, 大勢[たいせい]:general trend/current thought
大勢いるんだぜえ～！
かぶりつく:to bite into/to sink one's teeth into|to stick to
（コユキ）べ 別に
かぶりついてるわけじゃないぞ！
I-I'm not stuck on her!
ヘヘヘへ～ それ やるよ
じゃあな～ ウハハハ…
You can have it. See you!
What are the two of you stuck on?
かぶりつく:to bite into/to sink one's teeth into|to stick to
（益岡(ますおか)）２人して 何に
かぶりついてるんですか～？
ゲーム:game, 攻略[こうりゃく]:capture|strategy guide/playing guide (e.g. for game), 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（コユキ）あ いや ゲームの
攻略本… みたいな…
Uh, just a book that explains how to
conquer computer games...I guess...
Yeah, yeah...
Oh?
ふ～ん
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
（サク）コユキは真帆から
聞いてなかったの？
Didn't you hear about it
from Maho, Koyuki?
I haven't seen her lately.
She seems busy...
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless
最近 全然 会ってないし
忙しそうだし…
Oh, Saku-chan, you have a nosebleed.
鼻血[はなぢ, はなじ]:nosebleed
（益岡）あれ？
サクちゃん 鼻血 出てるよ
Ah!
Oh, Taira-kun! What's up?
平[ひら, ヒラ]:something broad and flat|common|low-ranking employee
お～う 平君かあ
うん どうしたの？
What?!
-What's the matter, Chiba-kun?!
-Yeah! I'll be right there!!
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ）どうしたの 千葉君!?
（千葉）うん！ すぐ行く！
千葉[ちば]:Chiba (city)
（コユキ・サク）どわあ！ 千葉君！
-Oh...Chiba-kun!
おおい:hey!/oi!|I, おおい:many/numerous|large quantity
（千葉）おおい!! 竜介～!!
Hey! Ryusuke!
Yo...
よう
散歩[さんぽ]:walk/stroll
（平）あいつ ベックの
散歩に行ってたんだとさ
He says he was out walking Beck.
包帯[ほうたい]:bandage/dressing, まみれ:covered with/stained/smeared
何で 包帯まみれなんだよっ！
Why are you all bandaged up?
竜介君 大丈夫？
Ryusuke-kun...Are you all right?
（サク）どこにいたの？
Where were you?
Where the heck are Beck and Lucille?!
おい！ ベックとルシールは
どうしたんだよ!?
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal
（竜介）ハハッ まあさ
女とか金とか—
Well...Money and women...
Don't ask awkward questions, will you?
ヤボなこと 聞くなよな
W-W-Women?
おっ おっ 女…？
Money?
お金[おかね]:money
お金？
Anyway...Beck and Lucille
won't be coming back.
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
とにかく ベックとルシールは
もう戻らないんだ
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
（平）ちょっと 話してくる
（千葉）あとでな！
-I'll go and talk to him.
-See you later.
Yeah...
Really, man...What were you doing?
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, おめえ:you (formerly honorific, now sometimes derog. term referring to an equal or inferior)|presence (of a god, nobleman, etc.)
（千葉）ホントに おめえ
何してたんだよ！
-Shut up, will you?
-Come on...Be nice.
仲良く[なかよく]:on good terms with/on cordial terms with|to make friends with
（竜介）うっせーなあ
（平）ほらほら 仲良くしろよ
Ryusuke-kun...
竜介君…
-It tastes a little different...
-Yeah...
Boy, our boss is really...
In other words...I wasn't worth killing.
価値[かち]:value/worth/merit, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being
（竜介）つまり俺は
殺す価値もない存在なんだ
金[おうごん, こがね]:gold, 金[かね, かな]:money|metal
〈そうさ 俺は金のためなら
人だって殺すだろう〉
Yeah...That's right. I do kill for money.
But I don't just murder people
for no reason.
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance, 殺人[さつじん]:murder, 主義[しゅぎ]:doctrine/rule/principle
〈でも 意味のない殺人は
しない主義だ〉
Now get the fuck outta here!
消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear, 泥[どろ]:mud/slush|thief
〈消えな コソ泥野郎！〉
心を動かす[こころをうごかす]:to impress/to move one's heart/to touch (a person's heart), 音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
こんな俺に 人の心を動かす
音楽なんて 作れんのかな
Can someone like me create music
that will move people?
（平）お前… 何 言ってんだ！
What are you saying?!
He's right! You're lucky to be alive!
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, なんぼ:how/how much|under no circumstances, じゃん:isn't it
（千葉）そうだよっ
生きて なんぼじゃん！
（コユキ）ねえ サク これ見て！
Hey, Saku! Look at this!!
"Pro-Am Welcome Auditions!!"
This would be a great chance!
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), チャンス:chance/opportunity, じゃん:isn't it
これって すごいチャンスじゃん！
"Pro-Am Welcome Auditions!!"
Ohh...Auditions!?
オーディション:audition
（サク）
へえ！ オーディションかあ…
Ohh...Auditions!?
教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
竜介君に教えてあげようよ
Let's tell Ryusuke-kun about it.
Good idea!
そうだね！
（コユキ）あっ！
I don't know about that...
かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
（和緒(かずお)）
え～ それはどうかしら？
-Huh?
-Uh...
えっ？
（サク）あの～
オーディション:audition, か月[かげつ]:months (period of), 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
（和緒）そのオーディションなら
２か月前に終わってるわ
Those auditions were over two months ago.
（コユキ）え？ そんな…
Huh? No way...
だいたい:outline/main point|general, だいたい:battalion, グレイ:grey (gray), トフル:Test of English as a Foreign Language/TOEFL, サウンド:sound, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
だいたい グレイトフルサウンドの
準備は １年かけてやるのよ
Besides, bands prepare a whole year
for that Grateful Sound event.
（サク）あっ あなたは…
A-And you are?
For your information,
the band that was chosen
ちなみ:association/link|pledge (esp. for marriage), オーディション:audition, 合格[ごうかく]:success/passing (e.g. exam)/eligibility, バンド:band
ちなみに そのオーディションで
合格したバンドは—
ラ・マヒストル
was a promising newcomer called
"La Majistol" on the Ran label.
蘭[らん, ラン]:orchid|Holland/The Netherlands, 蘭[あららぎ, アララギ]:Japanese yew (Taxus cuspidata)|wild rocambole (Allium grayi), レーベル:label (i.e. sticker), 期待[きたい]:expectation/anticipation/hope, 新人[しんじん]:new face/newcomer|modern humans (from Cro-Magnon man onwards)
蘭(らん)のレーベルからの
期待の新人よ
Ran...
蘭[らん, ラン]:orchid|Holland/The Netherlands, 蘭[あららぎ, アララギ]:Japanese yew (Taxus cuspidata)|wild rocambole (Allium grayi)
（コユキ）蘭…
-In other words...
The contest was rigged.
-Uh, ma'am...
出来[しゅったい]:occurrence/happening/taking place, 出来[でき]:workmanship|grades|quality (e.g. of a crop)|, レース:race
つまり 出来レースってことね
（コユキ）あの オバさん—
-Ma'am?!
-This fishing hole is closed today.
オバ… さん？
んっ んんっ！
釣り堀[つりぼり]:fish pond, きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 定休日[ていきゅうび]:regular holiday/fixed day off/regular closing day
ここの釣り堀
きょうは定休日なんですけど
（和緒）ふん？
Huh?
Y-Y-Y-You...Are you the boy who sang
with Dying Breed in that Jim Walsh movie?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
ボ ボ ボ ボ…
ボク もしかして—
映画[えいが]:movie/film, 歌う[うたう]:to sing|to sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.)/to compose a poem, 少年[しょうねん]:boy/juvenile/young boy
ジム・ウォルシュの映画で
ダイブリと歌ってる少年!?
ええ そうですけど へヘッ
Yes. I am...
フッ これ～ あなたたちよね？
This...This is you guys, right?
Yes...
Mongolian Chop Squad is the
name of our band in America.
モンゴリアン:Mongolian (person), チョップ:chop
（サク）モンゴリアン・
チョップ・スクワッドは—
アメリカ:America, バンド:band
俺たちのアメリカでの
バンド名ですけど
やった:hooray/whee/hot dog!
（和緒）キャアアアッ！
やったわあああ!!
I did it! I finally found you!
I wasn't mistaken.
やっと:at last/at length|barely, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing, 間違う[まちがう]:to make a mistake/to be incorrect/to be mistaken
やっと やっと見つけたわ！
間違ってなかったんだ
My deductions were right,
after all! This is great!!
やっぱり:too/also|still, 推理[すいり]:reasoning/inference|mystery or detective genre, 正しい[ただしい]:right/correct|proper
やっぱり 私の推理は
正しかったんだわ！
もうっ サイコー!!
Hey! Didn't I tell you
not to let customers in?!
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
（竜介）おい 客は
入れんなって 言っただろ！
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（コユキ）あっ 客じゃないよ
っていうか 客だけど…
She's not a customer...
I guess she is...but not really...
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
いやっ そういう客ではなくて…
版[はん, ばん]:edition|plate|editions of a publication
（サク）あの人 俺たちの
ＵＳ版のＣＤ 聞いて—
-That lady heard our American CD
and used it to find us.
-Eeek! I hooked something!
What should I do?!
頼り[たより]:reliance/dependence
それを頼りに 来てくれたんだ
-That lady?
-Somebody, help!
あの オバチャンが？
ふう～ん
Hm...Metal Glue...
メタル:metal, グルー:glue
“メタルグルー 佐藤 わ お”？
"Wao Sato-Metal Glue, Inc."
-Wa...o...Sato?
-Phew! It smells fishy...
"Wao Sato-Metal Glue, Inc."
-Here. Give it to me, please.
-Huh? Huh? What should I do?
ハロー:halo
（竜介）ハロー？
-Hello?
-Hey, Ray...What the fuck're you doing?
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 英語[えいご]:English (language)
（真帆：英語）
〈おい 竜介 何してたんだよ！〉
Oh! I'm sorry, I'm kinda busy...
Just a sec...
忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless
（竜介）〈あぁ ワリィ
今 忙しいってゆうか〉
（竜介）おい！ コユキ
Hey! Koyuki...
Huh? What is it?
（コユキ）あっ 何？
Hello?
Koyuki?
（真帆）コユキ？
Ryusuke-kun's back safely.
無事[ぶじ]:safety/peace/quietness, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（コユキ）
竜介君 無事に戻ったよ！
He was probably over at some girl's.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best
どうせ 女のとこにでも
いたんでしょ～？
きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 先行[せんこう]:preceding/going first/leading, ロードショー:roadshow
あっ それよりさあ きょう
先行ロードショーなんだぞ
Never mind that...
There's a sneak preview of the
Dying Breed tour movie today!
ツアー:tour, ムービー:movie
ダイブリのツアームービー
What?! The Dying Breed movie?!
映画[えいが]:movie/film, もしもし:hello (e.g. on phone)|excuse me! (when calling out to someone)
（コユキ）ええっ!?
ダイブリの映画？ もしもし？
Hello?
Koyuki, you want to see it with me?
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
（真帆）
ね コユキ 一緒に見ない？
（コユキ）うん！
（サク・千葉）へヘッ
-Yeah!
-Mm...
（コユキ）俺 ちょっと…
-I gotta go...
-Yes! Go on!!
おーし！ 行ってこい！
（コユキ）サク？
（サク）へヘッ！
Saku...
（コユキ）
それじゃあ これ 竜介君に！
Okay! Give this to Ryusuke-kun, will you?!
青春[せいしゅん]:youth/springtime of life/adolescent
（平）いいねえ 青春しててさ
How nice...
He's enjoying his youth.
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
（真帆）遅いぞ～
You're late!
ハァ ハァ…
I just got a call from Yoshito.
ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
ちょうど ヨシトから
電話があってさあ—
He said he wanted to
see the movie too, so...
映画[えいが]:movie/film
ヨシトも映画 見たいって言うから
シチュエーション:situation
（ヨシト）男と２人っていう
シチュエーションは—
Being with two guys...
isn't very good for Maho's future.
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 将来[しょうらい]:future (usually near)/prospects
真帆の将来のためにも
よくないしね
アッハッハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly), アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
アッハッハ アハハ
プログラム:program/programme
ヨシト君 プログラム 見る？
Yoshito-kun, you want
to look at the program?
映画[えいが]:movie/film, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 主義[しゅぎ]:doctrine/rule/principle
俺 映画の前に
読まない主義～
I never read it before a movie.
Oh...
On the stage, they are perfect.
They're flawless.
Yes they are...And maybe not,
depending on your point of view.
Ahem. Excuse me...
Everybody has a life, a daily life.
There's no exception; they do.
Conflict with their agent?
It's none of our business!
Of course, Eddy. These guys
are the next big thing in Japan.
If we like them at the rehearsal,
yeah, we could play with them.
Belle Ame...It means
"beautiful spirit" in French.
Bugger off. Hit the road.
-Jim, give me that!
-After all, Eddy is just a guy.
-Hey! They're waiting for us.
-Why are you saying this now? Shit!
-But, that makes Dying Breed appealing.
-What shall we do? That's irresponsible.
Hey Jim! What are you filming!?
-On top of that, Matt is wild.
Like a river flowing,
inspiration always flows from my mind.
-Hey! Dancing, dancing...Party man...
-Oh! He's a funny guy.
-Happy birthday to you...
ハッピー:happy, バースデー:birthday
（一同）
ハッピーバースデー トゥー ユー
（男性）エディ！
Sometimes, there comes a special day,
while they're on tour.
It's a beautiful scene.
Tokyo...a city of noise
and chaos. Techno-city.
Come on!
They had a live here, as well.
In the evening, with the shining moon...
They met a boy. It was
a very special event.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen
（コユキ）何か すごいことが
起こりそうな—
I felt like something great...
予感[よかん]:presentiment/premonition|to have a premonition
予感がしたんだ
...was about to happen.
Another minute
Feelin' so fine
You turn the freeze
into warm light
Had a premonition
I've been waitin' ever since
My world comin' down
It's got me spinnin' 'round
If you really wanna fly
you gotta let go
Simply the most
big sensation
(once you're here you won't go back)
She's really pretty
One-eyed vision
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Little sister showed me
Really took me for a ride
My world comin' down
(once you're here you won't go back)
(lose the fear it don't come back)
おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing
（千葉）佐藤のオバチャンって
おもしれえよな！
That Sato lady was funny, wasn't she?
"Live 20
'Grateful Sound'”
Next episode: Grateful Sound!
Will Beck be able to perform?
次週[じしゅう]:next week
次週…
出場[しゅつじょう]:(stage) appearance/performance|participation (e.g. in a tournament), 出場[でば]:one's time (e.g. to go on stage)/one's turn|source
ＢＥＣＫは
出場できるのかな？